Qunfang Wu

♥ 343 Hinds Hall – Syracuse, NY 13244⋈ qwu114@syr.edu• 🛅 qunfangwu.com

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research lies at the intersection of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and social justice. Mainly, my research strives to challenge "platformed racism" – how socio-technical systems (e.g., algorithmic models, interface designs, governance structures) enable the construction and propagation of racist ideologies – and advocates for anti-racist design perspectives and practices. My dissertation work unpacked how Reddit users engaged in discourse frames that both re-enforce and fight against overt and covert racism and highlighted governance and moderation practices as color-blind on Reddit.

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Syracuse University Syracuse, NY, USA

Ph.D., Information Science and Technology, School of Information Studies

Anticipated in Aug. 2022

Advisor: Dr. Bryan Semaan

Dissertation: Conversations About Crime: Re-Enforcing and Fighting Against Platformed Racism on Reddit

Peking University

M.S. Information Science Description of Information Management

Beijing, China 2014-2016

 $M.S., Information\ Science, Department\ of\ Information\ Management$

Beijing, China

Peking University *B.S., Information Management and System, Department of Information Management*Minor in Economics, National School of Development, Peking University

2010-2014

GRANTS & AWARDS

- Summer Research Fund Competition, "Toward a Design Framework for Digital Equality: A Literature Review of Racialized Socio-Technical Mechanisms in Online Platforms", School of Information Studies (iSchool), Syracuse University (SU), 2022, \$6,500.
- Dissertation Fellowship, SU, 2021-2022, \$26,500
- Doctoral Students Awarded Summer Dissertation Fellowships, SU, 2020, \$4,000.
- Doctoral Colloquium Travel Funding, iConference, 2020, \$900.
- Summer Research Fund Competition, "Understanding Social Support Seeking Behaviors to Mediate Fear of Crime on Mobile Apps", iSchool, SU, 2019, \$6,500.
- Entrepreneurial Lead, "Beacon-Enabled Smart Location-Based Service", National Science Foundation (NSF) Innovation Corps (I-Corps), 2018, \$50,000. (PI: Dr. Yun Huang)

PUBLICATIONS

Peer-Reviewed Conference & Journal Papers

- [C.12] **Qunfang Wu**, Louisa Kayah Williams, Ellen Simpson, and Bryan Semaan. "Conversations About Crime: Re-Enforcing and Fighting Against Platformed Racism on Reddit". In: *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction* 6.CSCW1 (2022), pp. 1–38.
- [C.11] **Qunfang Wu** and Yun Huang. "Examining Police Agencies' Dialogic Accounting Practices in Facebook Conversations". In: *Digital Government: Research and Practice* 1.2 (2020), pp. 1–17.

Last updated: August 2, 2022

- [C.10] Yun Huang, Yisi Sang, **Qunfang Wu**, and Yaxing Yao. "Higher Education Check-Ins: Exploring the User Experience of Hybrid Location Sensing". In: *Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction* 3.CSCW (2019), pp. 1–26.
- [C.9] **Qunfang Wu**, Yisi Sang, and Yun Huang. "Danmaku: A New Paradigm of Social Interaction via Online Videos". In: *ACM Transactions on Social Computing* 2.2 (2019), pp. 1–24.
- [C.8] Yun Huang and **Qunfang Wu**. "Understanding Interactions Between Municipal Police Departments and the Public on Twitter". In: *International conference on information*. Springer. 2018, pp. 37–46. [Best Paper Award: Top 1].
- [C.7] **Qunfang Wu**, Saurabh Gupta, and Yun Huang. "Examining Conversations Between Police Agencies and the Public on Facebook". In: *Proceedings of the 19th Annual International Conference on Digital Government Research: Governance in the Data Age*. 2018, pp. 1–10.
- [C.6] **Qunfang Wu**, Yisi Sang, Shan Zhang, and Yun Huang. "Danmaku vs. Forum Comments: Understanding User Participation and Knowledge Sharing in Online Videos". In: *Proceedings of the 2018 ACM conference on supporting groupwork*. 2018, pp. 209–218.
- [C.5] Yun Huang, **Qunfang Wu**, and Youyang Hou. "Examining Twitter mentions between police agencies and public users through the lens of stakeholder theory". In: *Proceedings of the 18th Annual international conference on digital government research*. 2017, pp. 30–38.
- [C.4] Yun Huang, **Qunfang Wu**, Xing Huang, and Jennifer Bort. "A Multiplatform Investigation of Law Enforcement Agencies on Social Media". In: *Information Polity* 22.2-3 (2017), pp. 179–196.
- [C.3] **Qunfang Wu**, Xin Guo, and Jimin Wang. "Co-word Analysis on the Field of Marine Economy in China". In: *Proceedings of Chinese Society for Oceanography 2015*. Beijing: Maritime Press, 2015, pp. 336–342.
- [C.2] **Qunfang Wu**, Xiaoli Tang, and Jimin Wang. "Improvement and Empirical Research on Journal's First-Citation-Speed-Index". In: *Library and Information Service* 58.24 (2014), pp. 86–90.
- [C.1] **Qunfang Wu**, Xiaoli Tang, and Jimin Wang. "Relationship Between Non-cited Rates and Journal Evaluation Indicators: A Case Study in Economics". In: *Library and Information Service* 58.19 (2014), pp. 100–104.

Posters & Workshop Papers & Demos

- [E.8] Brian McKernan, Bryan Semaan, Louisa Kayah Williams, Isabel Munoz, Qunfang Wu, and Sucheta Lahiri. ""COVID as the Cherry on Top": The Impact of COVID-19 and Other Co-occurring Crises on Marginalized Communities' Identities and Worldviews". In: Proceedings of Eastern Sociological Society's (ESS) annual conference. 2022.
- [E.7] **Qunfang Wu**. "Development of a Community-Based Mobile Application: Facilitating Vulnerable Populations' Social Support Seeking for Managing Fear of Crime". In: *Doctoral Colloquium of International Conference on Information*. 2020.
- [E.6] **Qunfang Wu** and Yaxing Yao. "Towards Designing a Technology Ecosystem for Managing the "Fear of Crime"". In: *Workshops of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems: Crime and/or Punishment: Joining the Dots between Crime, Legality and HCI.* ACM, 2020.
- [E.5] Yun Huang, Yisi Sang, **Qunfang Wu**, and Yaxing Yao. "Studying User Experience of a Hybrid Location Sensing System". In: Extended Abstracts of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. 2019, pp. 1–6.
- [E.4] Yun Huang, **Qunfang Wu**, and Yaxing Yao. "Bluetooth Low Energy (BLE) Beacons Alone Didn't Work!" In: *Proceedings of the 2018 ACM International Joint Conference and 2018 International Symposium on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Wearable Computers*. 2018, pp. 62–65.

- [E.3] **Qunfang Wu** and Yun Huang. "Examining Q&A of Peer Tutor Learning via Online Videos". In: *Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems*. 2018, pp. 1–6.
- [E.2] Yun Huang and **Qunfang Wu**. "BandCaption: Crowdsourcing Video Caption Corrections". In: *Demos of the 2017 Collective Intelligence Conference*. 2017.
- [E.1] Yun Huang, Yaxing Yao, Jennifer Bort, and **Qunfang Wu**. "Danmaku: Understanding its Usage in China and its Broader Potential". In: *Workshops of the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing: CSCW in China and Beyond*. ACM, 2017.

Work in Progress

- [P.5] **Qunfang Wu**, EunJeong Cheon, and Bryan Semaan. "Toward a Design Framework for Digital Equality: A Systemic Literature Review of Anti-Racist Technology". In: (2022).
- [P.4] **Qunfang Wu** and Jeff Hemsley. "Conceptualizing the "Fear of Crime" on Reddit". In: (2022).
- [P.3] **Qunfang Wu**, Tayara Pena, and Bryan Semaan. "Moderation as Boundary Negotiation to Combat Racist Attacks in Online Communities". In: (2022). [Submitted to CSCW2023].
- [P.2] **Qunfang Wu** and Bryan Semaan. ""How Do You Quantify How Racist Something Is?": Color-Blind Moderation in Decentralized Governance". In: (2022). [Submitted to CSCW2023].
- [P.1] **Qunfang Wu**, Yisi Sang, Dakuo Wang, and Zhicong Lu. "Malicious Selling Strategies in Livestream Shopping: A Case Study of Alibaba's Taobao and ByteDance's TikToc". In: *arXiv preprint arXiv:2111.10491* (2021). [Submitted to TOCHI].

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

HCC+D Lab, School of Information Studies, Syracuse University Research Assistant

Syracuse, NY, USA *Jul.* 2020-*Apr.* 2021

COVID-19 Resilience Project

- Participated in grant writing: SU ICCAE Small Research Grants Program "Building Everyday Resilience with Technology: Exacerbated Marginalization in COVID-19" (PI: Dr. Brian McKernan; Co-PI: Bryan Semaan)
- Identified and maintained relationships with organizations (e.g., Office of Disability Services at SU, Aurora of CNY, Exceptional Family Resources) for participant recruitment
- Conducted 19 semi-structured interviews with participants who identified themselves as marginalized populations
- Analyzed the interview data and identified different experiences of racism pre and during the pandemic

SALT Lab, School of Information Studies, Syracuse University Research Assistant

Syracuse, NY, USA *Aug.* 2016-*Apr.* 2019

"SU Connect" Project (iOS and Android mobile apps)

- Designed, developed, and evaluated sensing mobile apps
- Led sensor (beacons) installation and server performance monitoring
- Conducted 100+ interviews for customer discovery and business model optimization in the NSF I-Corps project
- Analyzed database log data to identify user segregation and co-location patterns
- Conducted field studies to understand user behavior of using the opportunistic sensing system

"BandCaption" Project (a web-based online video system)

- Developed and evaluated a video system for online learning
- Participated in grant writing: NSF "Enabling Accessibility and Linking Digital Media Collections for Informal Online Learning" (PI: Dr. Yun Huang); 2U "Accessible and Personalized Online Social Learning"

Last updated: August 2, 2022 3/5

(PI: Dr. Yun Huang)

- Conducted statistical tests and content analysis about how users shared knowledge via multiple commenting modalities in videos
- Conducted a field study and analyzed system logs to understand Q&A norms in reciprocal peer tutoring via self-generated videos

Mercer College, Mercer China Consultant Assistant (Intern)

Beijing, China Oct. 2013-May 2014

- Collected and analyzed competitors' information
- Updated client databases and wrote monthly and yearly sale reports
- Responded to client questions about product, workshop registration and feedback

TEACHING

<i>d</i> , .	Summer 2022
• Instructor, Information Visualization, SU	Spring 2021
• Co-Instructor, Information Visualization (Instructor: Jeff Hemsley), SU	Fall 2020
• Teaching Assistant, Human Interaction With Computers (Instructor: Bryan Semaan), SU	Fall 2019
• Teaching Assistant, Privacy Policy, Law and Tech (Instructor: Yang Wang), SU	Fall 2017
• Teaching Assistant, Demystifying the Chinese Economy (Instructor: Justin Yifu Lin), PKU	
• Guest Lecturer, Social Media in the Organization (Instructor: Jennifer Sonne), SU	Summer 2019
• Guest Lecturer, Research Methods in Info Studies (Instructor: Caroline Haythornthwaite), SU Fall 2018	
• Guest Lecturer, Data Admin Concepts & Database Management (Instructor: Yun Huang)	, SU Fall 2016

STUDENT MENTORING

 Tayara Romero, SU Mechanical Engineering undergraduate Danielle Nimako, SU iSchool undergraduate 	2021-Now 2021
Christy Khoury, SU iSchool master student, now doctoral student at SU	2020-2021
• Louisa Williams, SU iSchool undergraduate, now doctoral student at University of Michigan 2020-2021	
• Tian Xu, SU iSchool master student, now doctoral student at University of Colorado Boulder 2019	
• Eldon Tsoi, SU iSchool undergraduate, now Global Technology Analyst at Bank of America	2019
Lingyun Ke, SU Computer Science master student, now Software Engineer at Meta	2018
Niti Saluja, SU iSchool master student, now Delta One Strategist at Morgan Stanley	2018
• Saurabh Gupta, SU iSchool master student, now Business Intelligence Engineer at Amazon	2018
• Jiayi Zou, SU Computer Science master student, now iOS App Developer at ByteDance	2017-2018
Yisi Sang, SU Education master student, now doctoral student at SU	2017-2018
Qiuyan Liu, SU iSchool master student	2017-2018
Sudan Zhuang, SU iSchool undergraduate, now Product Manager at Microsoft	2017-2018
Jianyi Liu, SU iSchool master student	2017
Shan Zhang, SU iSchool master student, now at Twilio	2017

SERVICE

External Service

- Reviewer, Psychology of Popular Media, 22'
- Reviewer, TOCHI, 22'

Last updated: August 2, 2022

- Reviewer, CSCW 20', 21'
- Reviewer, CHI 19', 21'
- Reviewer, iConference 19', 20'
- Reviewer, ASIST, 20'
- Reviewer, DIS 19'
- Reviewer, DG.O 18'
- Student volunteer, CHI 19'

Internal Service

- Search Committee, iSchool, SU, Fall 2019
- Faculty Committee, iSchool, SU, Fall 2018
- Personnel Committee, iSchool, SU, Fall 2017

SELECTED MEDIA PRESS

- Stars on a Bigger Stage. 2018. http://usa.chinadaily.com.cn/a/201804/18/WS5ad68fe1a3105cdcf6518e70. html
- Huang and Wu Take Best Paper Award in 2018 iConference. 2018. https://ischool.syr.edu/articles/news/view/huang-wu-take-best-paper-award-2018-iconference/
- Huang Awarded NSF I-Corps Grant for Technology Commercialization Research. 2018. https://news.syr.edu/2018/03/huang-awarded-nsf-i-corps-grant-for-technology-commercialization-research/

REFERENCES

Bryan Semaan

Associate Professor University of Colorado Boulder Bryan.Semaan@Colorado.EDU

Cliff Lampe

Professor University of Michigan cacl@umich.edu

Jeff Hemsley

Associate Professor Syracuse University jjhemsle@syr.edu